ALI PAJAND

Montreal, Quebec/Canada • ali.pajand@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/alipajand/ @ alipajand.com/en

Senior Frontend Developer

Summary

I'm an extroverted, energetic, highly positive and hardworking developer with +8 years expertises in web development (frontend) with a history of graphics knowledge.

My main affection is to learn about web and new technologies from various sources. I enjoy encountering challenges for which my problem solving ability manifests and expands. I love to see beautiful codes that have an adherence to standards and open-source solutions. I try to figure out all possible solutions but then act based on best practices and standard ways.

Work Experiences

Mar 2018 - Present

Senior Frontend Developer

Ctrl+Tech

- Implement websites and admin panels for: (Advva, Tazebar, Ctrltech, Admartiz, Banikar, Techtoman, Bidzila, FirouzehPlat,...)
- Implement PWA for some of application
- Implement attractive online chats and map segmentation based on vue and react
- Implement some custom service worker to work in offline mode
- Work with firebase messaging and other socket based services
- Design and implement email templates
- Write BDD tests for some of projects that are mentioned above

Jan 2014 - Dec 2017

Frontend Developer

Rayvarz Software Engineering

- Working in BPMS team (business process management system to rewrite online admin panel and portal in vue)
- Mentoring, UI Discussion and preparing prototypes for programmers
- Collaborate on service catalogue for Ministry of Economic Affairs of Iran
- Change user interface of eOffice to create new sense and change admin panel arguments and texts
- Maintain the old eOffice services and add new feature
- Start to implement new version of company website

Remote Experiences

July 2021 - Dec 2021

Senior Frontend Developer (Oslo, Norway)

BirdFlocks

Impletent main panel with next js framework in react as a single project

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

Senior Frontend Developer (San Francisco, US)

Galliot

Implement website and its admin panel in nuxt js framework in vue

Jan 2021 - May 2021

Senior Frontend Developer (Istanbul, Turkey)

Amoozal

Impletent main panel in nuxt and vue frameworks

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019 Frontend Developer (Vancouver, Canada)

Timely

Help to develop and maintain the global application in angular

Jan 2015 - Jan 2017 Frontend Developer (Lahti, Finland)

Lahtiprecision

Implementing three generation of website in these years

Education

Sep 2014 - Aug 2018 M.Sc. Computer/Information Technology Administration

Allame Tabataba'i University

Thesis: Identification of Factors to Use Cloud Computing by University Students in Educational

Process

Sep 2010 - Aug 2014 B.Sc. Engineering/Industrial Management

Allame Tabataba'i University

Skills

Vue js | Nuxt js

Pure version and **Nuxt** as ssr framework **Yuex** as State management tools

Familiar with **Typescript**

React Native

With $\underline{\textbf{Typescript}}$

Notifications and Service Workers

Onesignal & Google Firebase

Progressive Web Apps (PWA)

Python (Django) & Nodejs

Workbox

Familiar as a backend background and web api

React js | Next js | Gatsby

Pure version and **Next** as ssr framework **Redux** as State management tools

Familiar with $\underline{\textbf{Typescript}}$

Unit Tests

BDD and TDD tests with Jest, Mocha and E2E

Chrome Extension

Write some extensions for chrome browser

Version Controller

 $\mbox{\bf Git}, \mbox{\bf SVN}$ and $\mbox{\bf TFS}$

